One Pace Premium
Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
The Man Who Shook the World
Whitebeard's been...
Whitebeard's been impaled!
Oldtimer...
Who's done it?!
I think it's...
Well, the one who attacked him was a captain from Whitebeard's alliance...
One of the New World Pirates, Whirl Spider...
Squardo!
Why would you do such a thing?!
Answer me, Squardo!
S-Shut up! You're the ones who forced my hand!
What?! Do you have any idea what you've-
Old Man! If you keep pushing your body like this-
Old Man!
Drop the charade already, Whitebeard!
You made a deal with the Navy, didn't you?!
A deal to ensure that Ace and your
Whitebeard Pirates would get out of this alive!
What's Squardo talking about?
What's going on?!
He's lured us all into a trap!
I had no idea...
But Ace is the son of Gold Roger!
I was all alone when you found me...
Squardo is causing a scene again!
Is everyone here a total weakling?!
Come at me!
Bring me Gold Roger!
What's wrong? You lose your nerve?!
What's wrong, you guys?!
I'm sure you know why I was all alone...
It was because my cherished comrades, who I'd fought beside for so long...
were all killed by Roger!
I'm sure you know my hatred for Roger!
You could have at least told me that Ace is Roger's son...
Told me of your plans to make Ace the next Pirate King!
Ignore the Whitebeard Pirates!
Keep moving, pull back to the plaza!
The oldtimer wants to make Ace the Pirate King?
Whitebeard is the strongest pirate I know of.
I want to make him the Pirate King.
Even then, you had already betrayed me!
You let me become his friend, never knowing how you were mocking me!
And then your golden child Ace was captured!
Allied Ships
Human Weapons
The Whitebeard Pirates are within the bay,
while we allied crews are out here, along the shore...
You traded away the lives of the forty-three captains of your alliance...
in exchange for Ace's life!
The allied crews will be executed, while Ace and the Whitebeard Pirates are spared!
You and Sengoku have already agreed on that, right?!
Silence! You really expect me to believe that nonsense?!
You still don't get it?
You'll be eating your words soon enough.
If you think I'm lying, just watch closely!
The crews of the alliance will be the only targets of the attack that's about to begin!
The Navy has agreed not to attack the Whitebeard Pirates!
And what do you know? We came here for Ace's sake, for Whitebeard's sake...
to lay down our lives, unaware of the deception!
Look for yourself!
Just as he said, we're the only ones the Navy is attacking!
Whitebeard
Those monsters are coming in from behind,
and the left and right flanks are blocked by ice walls, meaning there's no escape!
Old Man! Is it true?!
Please say it's a lie, Old Man!
It's practically a miracle that I hit you even once.
I'm ready.
Kill me!
You know, we do seem to be their only targets!
Run!
Old Man! Did you really sell us out...
in exchange for Ace's life?!
Say something! Old Man!
Old Man! Old Man!
No way! There's gotta be some sort of mistake!
Whitebeard making a deal with the Navy?
Betraying his crew?
That's unthinkable!
This is Whitebeard we're talking about!
Whitebeard and the Navy made a deal?!
Does this mean the pirates who trusted Whitebeard and fought alongside him...
are betrayed and will be eliminated by the Navy?
I didn't want to believe it... I doubted my own eyes!
How could you betray us, Old Man?!
You idiot!
He was the one who took you in, Squardo!
Why don't you have faith in the Old Man?!
You've no right to say that, Marco!
You're the Commander of the First Division!
I refuse to hear you say that you didn't know... about Ace or about the deal with the Navy!
It's true that Ace is Roger's son...
So they found the man who'd be the most hurt to hear that, and turned him against us.
Their plan was one step ahead of my own.
Enough of this.
Aokiji!
Why is he coming here?!
So this entire war was arranged from the beginning?!
Then what was the point of all the fighting up to now?!
Does this mean neither of them will win?!
The broadcast died!
What's going on?!
Did it break?
Mobilize the walls!
That bastard... He was hit so easily, by one of his own allies!
You're a disgrace, Whitebeard!
I didn't know I'd lost to such a weak man!
Croco-boy...
Crocodile...
Yeah, it's true... In the past , you've always been able to dodge attacks like that...
Even injured or exhausted, or if the attack came from one of your own,
you've never been hit by an attack like this, and that's what's bothering me!
You want me to wear this equipment so the enemy will feel sorry for me or something?!
Old Man!
Your health is deteriorating.
You realize what you've done, don't you...
Squardo?
You've turned your blade against your own father...
You foolish son!
Though you're a fool, I still love you, my son.
Don't... try to trick me...
You... sold out our...
Who has dragged your pure, loyal heart into such darkness?
A Navy insurgent.
I'm against this plan.
Whitebeard is the one you ought to strike down in this war.
Going for anyone else would be a grave mistake.
If you'll cooperate with me, I'll save the allied pirates.
Kill Whitebeard.
He said he'd save the allied pirates if I killed you...
So that's what Akainu said...
I'm painfully aware of how you hate Roger.
But Squardo...
It's wrong to resent a child for the sins of his father.
What did Ace ever do to you?
Together, you and Ace have been through pain, joy, and difficulty,
rising above it every time, with your friends beside you.
It doesn't matter who Ace's parents were.
We got a chance to meet on this big, wide ocean.
Not only you two. All of you are my sons.
So Squardo, try to get along.
Don't think that Ace is a special case.
You are all my family.
Still...
you really...
haven't changed, Sengoku.
You sure duped him.
Me, sell out my own sons' lives?!
So he's given the pirates an escape route...
I shouldn't have taken him so lightly.
The wall of ice is gone...
We can commandeer the warships!
Now we can escape whenever we want!
If you're pirates, then decide for yourselves what to believe!
It was a lie after all! The Navy planned this whole thing!
Dammit! They conned us all!
There's no way the Old Man would betray us!
Forgive me! I'll never doubt you again, Old Man!
Me too, Old Man! Please forgive me!
Old Man! I'll follow you till the end!
Old Man!
A weak man, you say? Give me a break, Alligator-kid!
I'm only one man, with one heart.
They may call me a demon or a monster or whatever,
but I won't be the strongest forever.
If I can help just one young life rise to the future,
then it will be enough for me.
Those willing to come with me, follow me even if it costs you your lives!
Yeah!
Attack! He's on the move! The strongest man in the world!
Let's go!
Yeah!
Don't let them advance!
Fire!
Do as the Old Man says!
Open a path for the Old Man!
Whitebeard...
Squardo...
The Navy tricked him into going after the Old Man!
How stupid can you get?!
And how bad must he be feeling now?!
But then...
What...
have I done?!
I'm sorry, Old Man!
I'm sorry, Ace!
Squardo.
Are you gonna cry, or are you gonna make them pay?
That old guy sure is amazing... Even with that wound...
But I've got to focus on Ace!
Luffy-kun!
Jinbei!
Look at that!
All our enemies have retreated to the plaza without us noticing!
I have a bad feeling about this...
But the Old Man has made his move!
This is no time to be second-guessing!
Indeed! It's too late to stop now!
Still not ready?!
Sorry, Sir! The ice is much stronger than we anticipated.
Charge!
The walls should be up by now...
This is bad!
I'll buy us some time!
Vice Admiral!
I won't let you reach the plaza, Whitebeard Pirates!
I-It's one of the Navy's Vice Admirals, John Giant!
You're in our way.
My balance...
Vice-Admiral!
Hey! The ground is tilting!
Stay away from the Old Man!
This isn't just an earthquake!
The sea...
Unbelievable...
The whole island and the sea...
are being tilted!
What a crazy old geezer!
Luffy-kun!
Jinbei!
I've got you now!
You saved me... Thanks!
You needn't thank me.
Can't that guy tell his allies from his enemies?
His crewmates knew to take refuge by the flanks.
What awesome power...
But the Navy's Absolute Justice is at stake...
I can't let you pass!
It's not stopping!
It's gonna reach the execution platform!
Go! Tear it apart!
Hey... Is the execution platform still standing?
Did it work?
It didn't hit the execution platform?!
Why did it veer off?
T-That's...
The Three Admirals!
This happened because they didn't raise the walls in time.
Because your ice is in the way!
Why don't you just melt it, Sakazuki?
Let's go, Whitebeard Pirates!
Charge!
They all seem pretty fired up...
Scary!
What happened to the walls?
Sir, it's...
I don't care if we shut down the city's whole electric grid.
Use all the power we have to mobilize those walls!
Yes, Sir! Right away!
Ace!
Luffy!
I'm coming now!
Ace!
Power input, maximum!
W-What?!
W-Walls?!
We're surrounded!
What is this?!
Dammit!
Did I get it?
It's hopeless! It won't budge!
It must be incredibly dense steel!
So the walls they were talking about earlier were these enormous defensive walls?!
Dammit! So you're not gonna fight us then, Navy?!
Hey, look at that!
All the cannons are pointed at us!
Let's run away!
We're surrounded! Where are we supposed to...
There's an opening!
Hey! What's going on?!
Raise all of the walls!
Well... The walls can't handle the massive weight of Oars' body!
And it looks like his blood leaked into the system and damaged it!
Seriously? Damn demon!
Oars... You...
What an incredible guy!
He's still fighting... even now.
Admirable!
They may not be closed in...
but proceed with the operation, Akainu!
Meteor Volcano!
What's going on?!
We're not letting you escape!
Melt the ice and take away their footing!
Editing, Sewil
QC, Galaxy 9000, Pepperjack
Karaoke, KaitouYahiko
Timing, Sewil
Soundtracking, Halee
Translation, Yibis
Raws, Cruchyroll